Morning. Mr. Thrombey.
Mr. Thrombey? You up there?
Mr. Thrombey. I'm coming in.
Shit!
You killed him. you bastard!
You murdered him!
I didn't murder nobody!
You slashed his face open.
You left him bleeding in the street
like a stuck pig.
then you crushed his skull with a forklift
and burned his hands off
to erase the fingerprints!
You'll never prove it.
We have the nanny-cam footage!
Alice. turn that off now. please?
- Why? It's almost over.
- Now. Please. just turn it off.
They're finding out who did it
and the Wi-Fi sucks in my room--
- Turn it off. now. Alice!
- There's two minutes left.
- What? There isn't even anything bad on.
- Off!
It's just normal TV.
and they're just talking!
They're talking murder on it!
- They're just talking.
- Your sister just had a friend she loved
slit his throat open and she doesn't need
to be hearing that right now!
Let's be sensitive!
Alice. you can keep watching your show.
It's fine.
- No. I guessed who did it anyway.
- It's okay.
I'm sorry. Marta.
It's okay.
It's Harlan's son.
Hi. Walt.
Hi. Marta. It's Walt.
Would you mind coming to the house early?
The police have
a few more questions for everybody.
What?
Hey. Excuse me. ma'am.
You with the help?
Hey! Her name's Marta.
She was Granddad's nurse.
She's with us. "The help"?
It's okay. I'm sorry.
No. it's not okay. What the hell?
How are you doing?
Not very good.
Alone.
Lots of this
and not knowing what to do next.
Marta. anything you need...
You're part of this family.
Thank you.
- How you doing. kiddo?
- Linda.
How are you?
You know. the funeral helped. I guess.
Just seeing him.
I thought you should have been there.
- I was outvoted.
- Get arrested!
- Die up your own ass for all I care!
- Richard.
He's not coming.
Ransom. Little shit.
Missed the funeral.
Excuse me.
We're ready for you now.
We'd like to see you one at a time.
All right. I'll go first.
I'm assuming this will all be wrapped up
before the memorial tonight.
We'll do our best. ma'am.
So...
how you doing. kiddo?
We're just gonna reintroduce ourselves
as a formality.
I am Detective Lieutenant Elliott.
and this is Trooper Wagner.
Now. I'm going to record this.
just to make things easier.
All right. we're with
Linda Drysdale née Thrombey.
Harlan Thrombey's eldest daughter.
and discussing the events that took place
the night of his demise one week ago.
November 8th.
We're very sorry for your loss.
Thank you. That means a lot.
So. we understand on that night
the family had gathered
- to celebrate your father's 85th birthday?
- Yes.
- How was it?
- The party?
Pre-my-dad's-death?
Oh. it was great.
Did anyone besides the family show face?
Fran. the housekeeper.
He was a nice guy. but he was so hairy.
- Jacob?
- And I've dated Italian guys.
You know what I mean? It was like...
Marta. Harlany's caregiver.
Good girl. Hard worker.
Her family's from Ecuador.
And Wanetta.
Greatnana. Harlan's mom.
- Hi. Nana.
- His mom?
- Nana?
- Wow. How old is she?
We have no idea.
Okay... and your son. Ransom.
did he attend as well?
Yes. but he left early.
Ransom. are you leaving?
Right.
Would you say that all three of you
showed up around the same time?
No.
Richard came early
to help the caterers set up.
Okay. And you and your husband. Richard.
work at a real estate firm in Boston?
No. It's-- It's my company.
Right. Right. Sorry.
I built my business from the ground up.
Oh. just like your father.
You two were very close.
We-- We had our own secret way
of communicating.
I mean. you had to find that... with Dad.
You had to find a game to play with him.
and if you did that.
and you played by his rules...
Everyone idolizes their dad. right?
I don't know. Do they?
Very much not.
Don't know why I said that.
But my wife. Linda. does.
Harlan started out
with a rusty Smith Corona
and built himself into one of the
best-selling mystery writers of all time.
Wow. seems like all his kids
are self-made overachievers.
Sure.
For the record.
I'm speaking with Walt Thrombey.
Harlan Thrombey's youngest son.
So you run your father's
publishing company?
Yeah. It's my-- It's our--
It's the family's publishing company.
Dad trusts me to run it.
Thirty languages.
Over 80 million copies sold.
A real legacy.
You guys fans?
I mean. I don't do much
fiction reading myself. but--
Big fan. I'm a big fan.
I mean. his plots are just like...
Like. I won't spoil it for you but--
Okay. like Thousand Knives?
The cow and the shotgun.
Like. where do you come up with that?
Well. Dad said the plots just popped
into his head. fully formed.
It was the easy part for him.
So you're in the area. right?
So. you guys probably arrived
around the same time.
We all got here around 8:00.
My wife. Donna. she's my rock.
Jesus. Donna! Are you all right?
My son. Jacob. he's 16.
Very politically active.
The boy is literally a Nazi.
He's an alt-right troll dipshit.
Kids today with the Internet.
it's amazing.
So the night went well?
I mean. we're all gutted. but...
I was happy to have that night with him.
To be by his side.
to think about our books
and what we've accomplished with them.
It's like I can still feel his hand
on my shoulder.
Passing the torch.
So. we're here with Joni Thrombey.
Harlan Thrombey's daughter-in-law?
Yeah. I married his son. Neil.
We had one daughter. Meg.
And then Neil passed on 15 years ago.
But you remained close to the Thrombeys?
They're my family.
I feel simultaneously freed by
and supported by them.
It's that balance of opposites
that's the nugget of Flam.
Sorry. the nugget of...
Flam.
Oh. yeah. Flam.
your skin care company. Sorry.
I forgive you.
Yeah. it's skin care.
but it promotes a total lifestyle.
Self-sufficiency with an acknowledgement
of human need.
That's Flam.
But it's also Harlan.
He got me and Meg
through some tough times.
Granddad gives my mom a yearly allowance
and he's never missed wiring
a tuition payment to my schools.
He's a genuinely selfless man.
But you left the party early?
Have fun.
To see some friends at Smith.
You know Dad pays for her
crypto-Marxist-post-deconstructural-
feminist-poetry-theory-whatever major?
She could have stuck around for the cake.
I think Linda was upset.
But Harlan understood.
Right.
You two showed up to the party
around the same time--
If I could pause?
Because I just...
Who is that guy?
- And why are we doing all this again?
- These are just some follow-up questions.
We're attempting to be thorough.
so we can figure out the manner of death.
So by "manner of death."
you mean if someone killed him?
If one of us killed him?
- One of his family killed him?
- No. Walt-- Walt. no. no.
Is that what you're suggesting.
Lieutenant?
No one's saying that. okay?
This is all pro form a.
Okay.
So who the fuck is that?
This is Benoit Blanc.
- Benoit Blanc?
- Yes.
Mr. Blanc is a private investigator
of great renown.
Wait a minute.
I read a tweet about
a New Yorker article about you.
"The Last of the Gentlemen Sleuths."
You solved that case
with the tennis champ.
You're famous.
Mr. Blanc is not
with the police department
and not officially involved in the case.
but he's offered to consult.
Now I happily obliged.
and I can vouch for him.
Mr. Blanc. I know who you are.
I read your profile in the New Yorker.
I found it delightful.
I just buried my 85-year-old father
who committed suicide.
Why are you here?
I'm here at the behest of a client.
Who?
I cannot say.
But let me assure you of this.
My presence will be ornamental.
You will find me a respectful.
quiet. passive observer...
of the truth.
Fine.
Are we getting there?
Nearly. Um...
Harlan's nurse. she was at the party
in a professional capacity?
Marta?
I guess.
Harlan hired her to be around to take care
of whatever medical needs popped up.
But really. she's like part of the family.
Good kid.
Been a good friend to Harlan.
Family's from Paraguay.
Linda really likes her work ethic.
"Immigrants. We get the job done."
- I...
- From Hamilton.
Oh. Hamilton.
It's so good.
- I saw it at The Public.
- Oh!
May I just...
Then I'll recede. but...
as a self-made man myself.
I have to express my admiration
for how you followed
in your father's footsteps.
- Thank you.
- Just marvelous.
You know. the whole family too.
And Joni with her thing.
and Walt with his publishing empire...
It's...
Well...
Yes. I mean. Walt. he's done well
with what Dad gave him.
Not that it matters.
But really. Dad hands him a book
twice a year and Walt publishes it.
It's just not the same.
But surely Walt runs
the merchandising. adaptations.
film and television rights. I mean...
Are you baiting me. Detective?
You know he doesn't.
And if you think I am dumb enough
to be baited into talking family business.
into shit-talking my baby brother
in front of a police detective
and a state trooper--
Walt doesn't run shit.
Because there are no TV and film rights.
Harlan never allowed
any adaptations of his books.
Hated the idea.
No.
Yeah!
Drives Walt nuts.
'Cause that's where the real money is.
When Walt would get
a little Irish courage in him.
he'd get into it with Harlan.
Did he "get into it" at the party?
Oh. my God!
Come on. Dad!
Wouldn't leave him alone. the poor guy.
- Harlan finally had to give him the hook.
- ...their business affair guy...
I didn't hear what he said.
but he must've really
handed him his lunch.
'Cause Walt was like a wounded puppy
the rest of the night.
What? Richard said what?
No. Jesus. We did not get "into it."
I'm just trying to get
an accurate impression.
Harlan took you aside at the party.
When you returned. you were chastened.
What did Harlan say to you?
The Netflix guys.
their business affair guy.
He sent something over.
It's hard numbers this time.
And I just think this is a window
that's not gonna stay open.
We need to take advantage of it and then
you just need to look at the numbers!
- Yeah. Walt. look--
- Dad! Dad!
You-- You put me in charge of our books.
Let me be in charge!
Let me do this! Please!
They're not our books. son.
They're my books.
And this is not how I wanted
to have this conversation.
But you're right. you're right. It's--
It's unfair of me to keep you tethered
to something that isn't yours to control.
What?
No. I've done you a grave disservice.
All these years.
I've kept you from building something
of your own that was yours.
But you're not going to be running
the publishing house anymore.
You're free of it.
Wh--
Dad. are you firing me?
No. I--
We'll talk details tomorrow.
My mind's made up.
Good boy.
We talked. We had
a business discussion about e-books.
Jesus. It was nothing.
You want to talk about an argument.
hell. Ransom had an argument with him.
Ransom. that's...
Richard and Linda's son?
Look. we all love Ransom.
He's a good kid. We love him.
But?
But he's always been
the black sheep of the family.
And I'm not trying to--
I like to keep stuff like this
in the family.
But with Ransom. he's never had a job.
And Dad. for some unknown reason.
always supported him.
They have this love-hate bond. They fight.
But that night. God. they had a blowout.
About what?
Are you goddamn insane?
We couldn't make it out really.
but it was huge.
And it's strange they went
into another room to do it.
Usually they like to stoke up drama
in front of the whole family.
Speaking of getting into it...
You were at the house early
to help the caterers set up. Did...
Did you converse with Harlan at that time?
Well. he was there. We must have spoke.
In his study?
I don't think so.
You see.
I spoke with the caterer this morning.
She didn't see you helping her staff.
She did hear Harlan in a screaming match
with somebody that afternoon in his study.
Yeah. I don't-- Screaming match?
No.
But Joni was here too.
She was early. so it might have been her.
Maybe ask her.
These were two male voices.
Harlan shouted the phrase...
You tell her or I will!
"You tell her...
or I will."
Bells ringing?
That's none of your business.
You stay out of my marriage.
I know my daughter.
and she would want to know.
I've put all of it in this letter to her.
Tomorrow. she gets it.
Harlan. I'm warning you.
- No. she deserves to know.
- Stay out of my marriage.
She deserves to know.
and you're gonna tell her.
- The hell I am!
- You tell her or I will!
Yes. I know.
Yes.
Harlan had finally decided
to put his mom in a nursing home.
and Linda had always opposed that.
And I wanted to wait until we got back
to Boston to tell Linda.
so to avoid a whole scene.
and Harlan wanted me to tell her then.
That was it.
Sorry. Forgot.
The house?
Earlier. Richard said you were there.
I was at the house early.
To see Harlan?
To see Harlan.
Yes.
What were you seeing Harlan about?
It was just a mix-up with the...
the payment for Meg's tuition.
I'm-- I'm--
I'm sorry to press.
but what kind of mix-up?
Yeah. the school hasn't got the check yet.
I don't know why Alan didn't mail it.
Well. Alan didn't mail it
because he caught a discrepancy.
Alan's office has been wiring tuition
directly to the school
as per your request.
But Phyllis's office that handles
your yearly allowance
has been wiring tuition monies
directly to you as well.
You have been double-dipping Meg's tuition
and stealing from me--
...$100.000 a year.
for the past four years.
Harlan. I don't know
how this mix-up happened.
- but I swear to God--
- So. now I am writing
this tuition check. but you must know
that this is the last money
you or Meg will get from me.
Please. you don't understand--
Joni. I know it'll hurt.
but it's all for the best.
My mind's made up.
It was a money wiring issue
with the office at the school.
So I had to ask Harlan
to cut a check for the semester.
No big deal.
Well...
Why don't we. uh. just take
a little break and we'll resu--
Oh. no.
She's gone.
Richard!
Joni. have you seen Richard?
- No. I was just done with the--
- Okay. thanks.
No.
Damn it. Richard!
Richard?
Son of a bitch.
See. I might be a victim
of my own expectation here.
but when the great Benoit Blanc
comes knocking at my door.
I expect it's going to be about something.
if not extraordinary.
then at least interesting.
But I'm sorry.
this is an open-and-shut case of suicide
and quite frankly. Benny.
we're getting to the point
where I need to know
what we're doing here.
The method?
Throat slit?
Typical for a suicide?
Yes. I mean. that's dramatic.
But look around.
I mean. the guy practically lives
in a Clue board.
Come on. Benny. talk to me. all right?
Now. you tell me to invite
all of these people back
for questioning all over again.
I get it.
I've had boots on the ground
in this county for a while.
People are generally what they seem to be.
Not gonna find murderers in this family.
This is a pleasant family
with the usual quarrels.
but no possible motives for murder.
Where are you going?
Harlan Thrombey's nurse. Marta...
- Cabrera.
- Marta Cabrera. Please.
Miss Cabrera. you can just wait inside
- and we'll be with you in--
- Miss Cabrera.
I've been doin' a little pokin'.
You were hired on a part-time basis
as a registered nurse. yes?
Yes. I don't work for a VNA.
Harlan hired me directly.
Take a seat. please.
And you're paid a flat rate for...
how many hours a week?
Well. I started at 15. and then he...
he needed more help.
Medical help?
He needed a friend.
Does having a kind heart
make you a good nurse?
All right. Blanc. I mean. this is--
Yeah. yeah. Marta? We were just discussing
possible motives in the family.
I suspect that Harlan has told you
much unfiltered truth about each of 'em.
And a little bird has told me--
How shall I put this delicately?
You have a regurgitative reaction
to mistruthin'.
Who told you that?
Is it true?
Yes.
It's something I've had since I was a kid.
It's a physical thing that I...
Just the thought of lying...
Yeah. it makes me puke.
Really?
Is Richard havin' an affair?
Why do men instinctively
pull at loose threads on their parachutes?
What?
Richard?
- An affair?
- Yeah.
A yes or no will do.
No.
Oh. shit!
- Oh. my God!
- Dear girl. I'm sorry.
I assumed you were speaking figuratively.
- I have Wet-Naps in the car.
- All right. here.
Just take a sip of this.
Take that.
That's quite somethin'.
- Thanks.
- But I was obviously right.
Richard is having an affair.
His father-in-law found out
and confronted him.
"You tell her or I will."
Okay. but even if that were the case--
You all right?
- Yeah.
- Even if that were the case. I mean.
protecting a relationship as a motive.
that's weak sauce.
- You know that.
- Well. then there is Joni.
- Joni?
Lifestyle guru Joni? No.
Harlan was supporting her and her daughter
and that's the opposite of a motive.
And if that support was threatened--
Miss Cabrera. one moment. please.
- Yes. I just wanna get some Scope.
- Miss Cabrera...
Was Harlan plannin' on
cutting off Joni's allowance?
Oh. Joni.
What's up?
Oh. my God.
All right. don't answer that
if you're gonna puke again. please.
Meg said he paid the school directly.
Joni said he sent the money to her.
Both were true.
She was pocketing the double payment.
Harlan found out
and cut her off without a cent. Yes?
So she bumps him off for the inheritance?
Come on. no. have you seen her Insta?
She's an influencer.
No. Allowance as a motive?
Again. more weak sauce.
You're just dumpin' that vat
of weak sauce on me.
Granted. But she lied to me.
All three of them did.
Three?
Walter.
I see where you're going with this.
Harlan had turned Walter down before
regarding film rights.
but that night.
somethin' Harlan said shook him.
Now we look at the pattern.
Harlan was cleanin' house.
No wonder.
Did he plan to fire Walter?
Can I just wait inside?
I feel like I shouldn't be here.
Yeah. please. just wait inside.
Stay close. all right?
You have been very patient. my friend.
And yes.
you are right.
None of these weak alibis
and domestic squibbles
answer your question.
"Why is Benoit Blanc here?"
Well. now I will tell you why.
I'm here because this mornin'.
someone dodged a very important question.
Who?
Me.
Linda asked who hired me.
Well. who hired you?
I do not know.
An envelope of cash showed up
at my apartment yesterday
with a news clippin' of Thrombey's death.
An envelope? That worked?
An envelope of cash.
So somebody suspects foul play
and goes through
this ha-cha dance of hiring me.
of staying anonymous.
It makes no damn sense.
Compels me. though.
Walk me through everyone's whereabouts
at the time of death.
We know that the party ended around 11 :30.
- Good night. Joni.
- Night.
Marta took Harlan upstairs
to give him his meds.
The stairs leading up to Harlan's bedroom
and his attic office creak horribly
and Linda is a light sleeper.
So we know every time
someone took the stairs that night.
The first was when Joni heard a ka-thunk
from somewhere above her in the house.
She's concerned about Harlan.
so she goes up to investigate.
Waking Linda.
Harlan was in his attic office with Marta.
- Hi. Joni.
- I just-- Hi.
He explained that they had
knocked over the Go board.
I just knocked over the Go board. so...
That game with the grid and stones.
They play it every night.
He was fine. "Go to bed."
Go to bed. Joni.
- Love you. Night.
- Love you.
- So she did.
- Bye.
Ten minutes later.
Linda is awoken a second time.
By Marta leaving.
Walt. I'm leaving.
Walt was smokin' a cigar
on the porch with his son.
He saw her leave and drive off.
Noted the time.
Midnight.
Fifteen minutes later.
Linda is awoken for the third
and final time...
...by someone coming down the stairs.
Harlan. who came down
for a midnight snack.
Dad. go back to bed.
Which Walt tried to discourage.
Based on this. the medical examiner
determined the time of death
to be between 12:15 and 2:00 a.m.
As Walt was finishing his cigar
at about 12:30. Meg came home.
She went straight to bed.
Walt and Jacob
turned in shortly after that.
And sometime later that night.
it's undetermined.
but possibly near 3:00 a.m..
Meg woke up because
the dogs were barking outside.
She used the bathroom. went back to bed.
That's it. All right?
Now. everyone's stories matched.
every moment accounted for.
And there is no other staircase
up to Harlan's room?
None. Just the creaky one.
Interesting.
So. uh. we know that Ransom didn't do it
because he wasn't there.
Marta couldn't have.
Harlan was still alive when she left.
- Yeah.
- Meg...
Meg came home during the window
of the time of death. right?
Except it was a suicide. all right?
Harlan slit right through his carotid.
We saw from the blood splat patterns
that they were uninterrupted.
meaning it's almost impossible for anyone
to have been around him at the time.
He's the one who cut his own throat.
I don't know why we keep goin' over this.
Physical evidence can tell a clear story
with a forked tongue.
- What?
- And as we can see from this mornin'.
everyone can lie.
Well. almost everyone.
Miss Cabrera...
We kept you waiting all afternoon.
because I wanted to hear from you last.
I needed an entire picture
of the evening in my head.
and your piece of it
is at its very center.
So. please. take your time.
You took Mr. Thrombey upstairs at 11 :30
and left at midnight.
Think very carefully
and with as much detail as possible.
Tell us what happened in that half hour?
- Up. up. up. I got it.
- You got it?
Up. up. up. I got it.
- Up. up. up. I got it.
- Okay. that's--
- Hey. Harlan.
- Up. up. up. I got it.
- Let's--
Up. up. up. I got it.
- Okay.
- No second thoughts.
No. No. no. no. no.
- Get up here!
- I had a glass of champagne.
- Harlan. listen to me.
- We are--
- It's late. I had--
- You only had one glass.
Exactly. A glass of champagne.
We are not breaking tradition
on my birthday!
Can you just take your goddamn medicine
and go to bed?
If you're gonna put that vile shit in me.
you have to earn it.
On my birthday.
- Oh. God.
- Eighty-fifth birthday.
- Fine. Jesus!
- I'm so old.
- You really love drama. huh?
Okay. let's do this. Nine-by-nine.
- Right.
- You ready?
- I'll whip your ass.
- Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah.
How dare you.
I know how this is gonna end.
What is that?
Why can't I beat you at this game?
Because I'm not playing to beat you.
I'm playing to build a beautiful pattern.
That's elder abuse.
I'm gonna call the AARP.
Don't make me get the belt. abuelo.
It's basically over.
My only hope
is that an earthquake will strike.
But what are the chances?
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Get under a door frame!
Yes!
Such a bad loser you are! Meds. then bed.
I'm done with you.
That's fair.
Walt is smoking that filthy cigar
out there on the porch.
Dead and nasty things.
How was tonight?
Tonight was... good.
Oh. yeah?
I know you weren't looking forward to it.
No. But I did it.
I cut the line on all four of 'em.
Yeah.
Wasn't easy.
This goddamn fortune.
You know. sometimes I think
that everything I've given my family.
I've done maybe
without knowing.
or maybe to keep them beneath me.
I certainly should have...
I don't know. encouraged Walt
to write his own stories. not just be...
a caretaker of mine.
Like you said I should.
And then be a father
and not just a provider
for Joni. like you also said.
And I could have been kinder
to Linda and Ransom.
Jesus! Ransom.
There's so much of me in that kid.
Confident. Stupid.
I don't know. protected.
Playing life like a game.
without consequence.
Until you can't tell the difference
between a stage prop...
and a real knife.
You know. I don't fear death.
But. oh. God.
I'd like to fix some of this before I go.
Close the book with a flourish.
I guess we'll see.
I guess we will.
Hey.
You had a long day.
You wanna do drugs?
You mean the good stuff?
Yeah?
Oh. come on. send me to la-la land.
Just a tiny bit. okay?
Why did I wait till my mid-age
to become a morphine user?
What a schmuck.
What a nudnik. This--
This stuff is the best.
Oh. my God.
Is there a problem?
This is what I just gave you
100 milligrams of.
I messed up.
You gave me 100 milligrams
of the good stuff?
Excuse me. but what is the good stuff's
dosage supposed to be?
Let's not call it that right now. okay?
Three milligrams.
Oh. that's much less.
So what happens?
I'm gonna give you
an emergency shot of Naloxone.
so you don't die in ten minutes.
Oh. well. no pressure.
You know. this is an interesting
and efficient method of murder.
I need to write this down.
So. if someone switched
the meds on purpose.
I'd be dead in ten minutes.
- Like stone-cold dead?
- Yes.
You'll feel symptoms in five.
Sweats. disorientation. and then...
Yes. That big dose injected.
within ten. your...
Your brain--
Yes. ten minutes.
From the moment of injection?
It's eight-ish now.
And even if the victim called
for an ambulance
when he first felt the symptoms
and if he lived in a great
big country house like we do.
the ambulance would take
at least 15 minutes to arrive
and then it'd be too late.
If the victim didn't have
the emergency Naxostuff.
Marta?
- Do you have the Naxostuff?
- Yes. I'm gonna find it.
I have it because it comes with the kit.
so it should be here. It has to be.
It's like...
It's not here. Harlan.
I don't know why it's not here.
So. I'm gonna use the phone. okay?
To call an ambulance.
What are you doing?
Marta. listen to me.
- Harlan. I need to call the ambulance.
- Stop this. Marta!
- There's no time! You have to listen!
- I'm calling the family!
What are you doing?
Are you nuts?
- Harlan. we have to call the ambulance.
- Listen to me. Listen to me!
Now. if what you said is true. I'm gone.
There's no saving me.
No. no.
We have six minutes.
- No. I can't--
- We have got to get you out of this!
Think of your mom.
My mom?
Marta. get behind me. get behind me.
Don't make a noise.
Harlan?
Marta?
Everything all right?
- Oh. hi. Joni.
- I thought I-- Hi.
I thought I heard something.
Is everything okay?
No. no. We're fine. We're fine.
Well. I just knocked over this Go board.
Sorry about that.
- Everyone's all right?
- Yeah. fine.
No. no. Go to bed. Joni.
Okay.
Maybe we can talk tomorrow
about the family...
Tomorrow's fine.
- Good night. Love you. Night.
- Love you. Bye.
Come on.
Pay attention. now.
Your mom is still undocumented.
And if this is your fault.
she'll be found out and at best deported.
and your family will be broken.
We're not gonna let that happen.
are we. huh?
But you have to do exactly
what I tell you.
Will you do this. Marta?
This last thing...
for me. for your family?
What do you want me to do?
Go downstairs as noisily as you can
and then say goodbye loudly.
Walt. I'm leaving.
- Call attention to the time...
- God. it's midnight already.
...if you can.
Drive out the gate.
Then to avoid the security cameras.
pull off the road
before the carved elephant.
- Wait. Was it before or after?
- After the carved elephant.
No. he said before. Was it?
- Beafterfore the carved elephant.
- Oh. shit.
Park. and come back
on foot up to the house.
Take the side yard pass
through the little gate.
The dogs will know you.
They shouldn't bark.
You've got to get up to the third floor
without being seen.
And the only way
is to climb the side trellis
and come in through the trick hall window.
You gotta be kidding me.
I am not. Do it.
And for God's sake. don't make any noise!
Once you're inside.
and this is the tricky part...
This is the tricky part?
Get my robe and cap from my bedroom
and put them on.
Harlan...
This is crazy.
I don't think I can do that.
No. we need to make this so airtight
that the average cop
will entirely dismiss you as a suspect.
It sounds crazy. but it'll work.
Walt is smoking outside. and he'll see you
through the glazed window.
Dad? Go back to bed.
You were seen leaving.
The security cameras show you driving off.
And 20 minutes later.
I'm seen alive and well by my son.
You see.
you've gone from suspect number one
to an impossibility.
Leave the way you came
and don't be seen.
Ransom?
Are you back again already?
Drive home.
And sometime in the next few days.
the police will question you.
No. No. no. no.
No. I can't lie!
You know I can't lie! I'll puke!
Well. then don't lie.
Tell fragments of the truth.
In this exact order.
I took him upstairs.
We played our nightly game of Go.
At some point. he knocked the board over
and Joni came up to check on us.
I gave him pain medication.
He pulled his shoulder last week.
And I left him in his study.
At midnight
I said goodbye to Walt...
went home.
What kind of medication did you give him?
Since his injury. I've been giving him
100 milligram IV push of Toradol.
It's a non-narcotic analgesic.
And to help him sleep.
three milligrams of morphine.
And the family was aware of this?
Yes. of course.
Did you notice anything strange
or off about his demeanor?
No.
Well. that sounds about right.
Thank you. Miss Cabrera.
Hey. sis. people are gonna get here
for the memorial pretty soon.
Are you--
Are you all right?
I was just thinking about Dad's games.
This all feels like one.
Like something he'd write. not do.
I keep waiting for the big reveal.
Where it'll make sense.
Wouldn't that be nice?
Oh. Walt.
I don't think he killed himself.
I don't. I really don't.
There's this Hallmark movie
called Deadly by Surprise
with Danica McKellar.
And in it. she plays this wife
who's getting poisoned by her husband.
but he's doing it little by little.
so she doesn't know it
and she goes crazy. and she kills herself.
And my cousin. who's a receptionist
at the medical examiner's office.
she says that stuff totally happens.
It's not even 3% as crazy as
the stuff she's seen come through there.
So. I'm just like...
Oh. God. yeah!
I mean. don't like him
because you love him.
No. I don't like him. He's an asshole.
But maybe an asshole is what we needed.
Oh. my God. yeah.
an asshole is what Germany needed
- in 1930-whatever.
- Here we go.
Come on. Joni. those two things
don't even conflate.
- There is the problem right there.
- Jesus.
I'm gonna disappear
until the politics talk is done.
You want some champers?
I can't. I'm technically working.
Why don't you take off your red cap.
Richard. and look around you?
The streets are literally
flooded with Nazis.
No. no. no. No. no. no.
We are losing our way of life
and our culture.
- That's right.
- There are millions
- of Mexicans coming.
- Oh. God. really?
Don't make this a race thing.
You always make this a race thing.
I would say the same thing
if they were European immigrants.
Oh. yeah? So. if the Swiss were. like.
- clogging in the streets--
- No. we allow them in
and they think they own what's ours.
They're putting children in cages!
I mean. these are camps!
Come on. Joni.
nobody's saying that isn't bad.
but the parents have some blame here.
Oh. for what? For wanting
a better life for their kids?
- Isn't that what America is--
- For breaking the law!
- My God.
- You're gonna hate hearing this.
- but it's true. America is for Americans.
- Don't point at me.
- Where's Marta? Is she still here? Marta!
- Oh. God. don't.
- Come on over.
- No. Richard.
- Come on over. Marta. Please.
- You're shitting me.
Marta.
your family is from Uruguay.
but you did it right.
I mean. what I'm saying is
they did it legally.
She did it the right way.
You work hard. and you'll earn your share
from the ground up.
Just like Dad and like all the rest of us.
And I'll bet you agree with me. right?
Oh. just leave the poor girl alone.
Richard.
It's okay! I just wanna hear
what she has to say!
It's okay. Marta. you can speak.
Sweetheart. don't feel
pressure to answer. This is just--
Look.
- Please don't.
- If you wanna become an American.
there are legal ways to do it.
But if you break the law.
it doesn't matter how good your heart is.
you gotta face the consequences!
Are you goddamn insane?
- It's done.
- Hey! I'm warning you.
That's when I ask her. "Tonya.
what is wrong with people?" Literally.
Oh. my God! Marta. what?
Marta?
What's the matter?
Whoa. whoa. Hey. Breathe.
- Oh. my gosh.
- Marta. are you okay?
Hey. Fran. do you still have your stash?
Take 'em whenever you need 'em.
They're just drying out
since you gave me that Juul.
Thanks. Fran.
- Hey. Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- No. just--
I'm very. very sorry.
- Stop saying you're sorry. Jesus!
- I hate this.
Oh. God. my heart won't stop. I can't--
It's just everything--No. thank you.
That's where Fran keeps her stash?
Who's gonna open a clock?
Do you want dinner. Nana?
Dinner? To eat?
- To eat?
- Walt.
- Nana?
- Walt. Walt. she's fine.
She ate the entire salmon spread already.
Walt? Did you tell Marta yet.
what we all talked about?
No. not yet. Is now a good time?
Yes. Yes. a very good time. right now.
Oh. okay.
All right. Calm down.
Marta.
we've been talking it over and...
- Have you been smoking grass?
- No.
Come on.
Marta. we've been talking it over.
and the whole family.
we'd like to take care of you.
Wha-- What does that mean?
We all think that you deserve something.
Financially we'd like to help you out.
You were never anything but good to Dad
and because of that we...
You can count on us.
Yeah.
I thought you should've been
at the funeral.
By the way. I was outvoted.
Detective.
You're still here?
Did you know Harlan?
He knew my father.
who was a police detective years ago.
My father respected Harlan.
That says quite a lot.
Is that why you're here?
Here now. here?
No.
I stayed hoping to speak to you
a little more.
Something is afoot with this whole affair.
I know it.
I believe you know it. too.
So you're gonna keep digging?
Harlan's detectives. they dig.
They rifle and root.
Truffle pigs.
I anticipate the terminus
of Gravity's Rainbow.
Gravity's Rainbow?
It's a novel.
Yeah. I know.
- I haven't read it though.
- Neither have I.
Nobody has. But I like the title.
It describes the path of a projectile
determined by natural law.
Et voilá. my method.
I observe the facts
without biases of the head or heart.
I determine the arc's path.
stroll leisurely to its terminus.
and the truth falls at my feet.
The medical examiner was ready
to rule this a suicide.
but Elliott agreed to keep it pending
for 48 hours.
Tomorrow morning.
I search the grounds and the house.
begin my investigation.
I want you to be by my side for it.
- What?
- My confidante.
- My eyes and ears.
- Hey. Wait. wait. Detective. Why me?
I trust your kind heart.
Also. you're the only one who had nothing
to gain from Harlan's death.
So how about it. Watson?
Hey. Detective?
If you want my insight into the family...
None of them are murderers.
That's my insight.
And yet.
be it cruel or comforting.
this machine unerringly
arrives at the truth.
That's what it does.
Always?
Tomorrow at 8:00.
I know I've missed something.
There's gonna be something I missed.
-Harlan. No. I can't.
- But I know you can do this.
Without losing your soul.
you have to do what you have to do...
- No.
- ...to beat this and win.
Harlan. I can't.
- You can. And you have to.
- No.
For me.
Right now!
Harlan. I have to get you help.
You do as I say...
and everything will be just fine.
No.
- No.
- I promise.
But--
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
Fifty years ago. I worked this estate.
You know. security back then was such that
you had to make the rounds with a 94
and keep your ears open.
Now you've got all this modern technology.
Now. that's the video there.
I saved the tape from that night.
Normally. I erase 'em
with a magnetic degausser.
but in this case.
I thought I'd just save it. you know?
For security.
Now. that's a live feed there.
To avoid the security cameras.
pull off the road
after the carved elephant.
All right. well.
can we see the actual tape?
Well. of course you can.
I recorded it SSLP.
There's eight hours in that tape.
9:00 p.m. to 5:00 a.m.
Looks like a Japanese horror movie.
You think we could scan forward on that?
Are we all gonna die in seven days?
How can we scan forward?
Oh. yeah. just hold the play button down
and press FF until you hear it grind.
All right. Should be coming up now
to the time when the party ended.
What happened?
You gotta keep holding it down
or else it'll eject.
That thing eats tapes like popcorn.
You think your guys can digitize this
so we could scan it properly?
Yeah. I think we can do that.
I got it.
You know all these statues
that you see around here?
They're all straight out of his series.
The Menagerie Tragedy Trilogy.
- Pretty cool.
- Awesome.
Yeah.
Benny. it's beautiful out here.
but do you really think someone broke
into the house and murdered Harlan?
- Is that why we're out here?
- It is unlikely.
but if they did. there will be traces.
- I can hang on to that.
- Yeah.
Hey. Wagner. you got any luck on...
- Uh. what's-his-name?
- Ransom?
- Yeah.
- No.
Did get an address though.
- Yeah?
- 10 Kenoak Street.
10... Kenoak?
Kenoak.
It's a pleasant thing to say. isn't it?
I awoke amid Kenoak.
- That's funny. Ken-oh-kia.
- All these leaves and mud.
they're really gonna do
a number on my boots. man.
Mud. Did it rain the past week
or something?
- No. stay there!
- What?
Whoa!
Okay.
We got footprints here. so. uh...
I wanna. um...
Marta.
- Stop.
- What?
What?
Marta. stay there.
- What?
- No. Marta! Stay there. Marta.
- No! No!
- I couldn't hear. If you--
- Did you call me?
- All right.
- Excuse me. Come here.
We're gonna need to call the boys.
have 'em come down here.
take a look at all these tracks.
- Get it taped off. Stay on that side.
- I'm sorry.
- Watch out.
- Okay.
Hey! Yeah!
Hussie? Hussie. hey.
Best judge of character is a dog.
- Good boy.
- I've found that to be true.
I'd...
Yes!
My puppies!
Yeah. well. they've got plans
to read the will at around 10:00.
so the whole family will be here soon.
- I've never been to a will reading.
- Oh. well...
You think it'd be like a game show.
but think of a community theater
production of a tax return.
So. what are we looking for?
Oh. you know.
anything suspicious
or out of the ordinary.
You'll know it when you see it.
Oh. my God.
Sweet beans!
Well...
Good morning. Mrs. Thrombey.
You think you could handle the study?
Where's your medical bag?
I don't know. I left it here.
I always leave it here
with Harlan at night.
They must have taken it in as evidence.
I'll look into that.
Shit.
How'd the Go board get knocked over?
We were just goofing around.
What are you thinking?
No! No. no. no! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Oh. let me guess.
Hey! Stop. Stop.
Stop. Stop.
Hugh Drysdale?
Ransom. Call me Ransom.
It's my middle name.
Only the help calls me Hugh.
- Okay.
- This is Trooper Wagner.
I'm Lieutenant Elliott.
We just wanna ask a few questions.
Excuse me?
Sir?
We're officers of the law!
You gonna run me in?
I don't feel like talking. I'm distraught.
Hey. Benny. you wanna ask
this guy some questions?
- What is this? What's this arrangement?
- Mr. Drysdale.
CSI KFC?
Hey. Frannie.
how about a glass of cold milk?
Hey. asshole.
Not her name. not her job.
Hey. Meg. How's the SJW degree coming?
- Trust fund prick.
- All right. guys.
Hey.
Hey. Everyone.
I'm just gonna be
in the other room. setting up.
Be ready in ten minutes.
Funny. Ransom. you skipped the funeral.
but you're early for the will reading.
Okay. people grieve in different ways.
Let's not...
You know what?
It's funny you're here at all.
Why are you even bothering?
That's what I'm asking myself.
What's that supposed to mean?
He knows what it's supposed to mean.
Wait-- Walt. what?
Jacob was in that bathroom
the night of the party.
That's where you were all night?
What the hell were you doing
in the bathroom all night?
- Nothing.
- Swatting Syrian refugees?
- No. I was not.
- Alt-right troll.
Liberal snowflake.
I don't know what any of that means.
It means your son's a little creep.
My son's a creep?
Guys. just--
Walt. he was in the bathroom.
Yeah. he was in the bathroom.
Joylessly masturbating
to pictures of dead deer.
You know what. Richard? You wanna go?
You bet. skippy. let's go.
You wanna go? Come on!
You better watch out. man.
- No!
- Stop!
Come on. I have been waiting
for this my whole life!
- Stop it. right now!
- Donna. I can handle myself!
- Stop it!
- I can handle it.
Oh. my God.
We gotta do this more often.
Hey!
Jacob.
We know where this is going.
You were in the bathroom
next to Harlan's office.
where he had the fight with Ransom.
Now. you heard something.
Spill it.
I just heard two things.
...my will.
"My will."
And then there was more yelling.
And then I heard Ransom say...
"I'm warning you."
Ransom...
What's that mean?
I think it means our father
finally came to his senses
and cut this worthless little brat
out of his will.
So I guess you're gonna have
to sell the Beemer
and give your notice at the country club
and kick whatever fashion drug you're on.
Because if you think
that after all the bridges you've burned.
after all the shit you said.
after everything that you put
this family through
for the last ten years.
that any of us are gonna support you.
that any of us are gonna give you.
like Dad liked to say.
"a single red dime."
you're nuts!
Wow.
Son...
Father.
Did Harlan tell you
he was gonna cut you out of the will?
Yep.
Well. then he's done
what none of us were strong enough to do.
Maybe this might finally make you grow up.
This might be the best thing
that could ever happen to you.
Thank you.
My mother. ladies and gentlemen.
Look. this is not gonna be easy for you.
but it'll be good.
Nothing good is ever easy.
Up your ass. Joni.
You've had your teeth
in this family's tit for a long time.
"Up your ass"? Oh. very nice.
- Matter of fact. eat shit.
- Oh. my God. Ransom.
- What?
- How's that?
Please do not use that word
in front of my son.
- In fact. eat shit. Eat shit.
- If I wasn't practicing--
- Eat shit.
- You entitled prick!
I would slap that smug smile--
- Definitely eat shit.
- ...off your goddamn face!
Eat shit. You can all eat shit.
I'm not eating one iota of shit!
What was that about
will readings being boring?
The exception that proves the rule.
Asshole.
"I'm warning you."
Ransom said. "I'm warning you."
Well. you heard Ransom in there.
That's the kind of thing he says.
You want this? You want this?
What do we have here?
This looks like a relatively fresh break.
Yep. Right there.
Wait a minute.
Well. that doesn't make sense.
Where's that window?
How about some more cookies. Hugh?
- You want some more cookies?
- That's great.
Hey. maybe Harlan left you
a cold glass of milk in his will. Asshole.
Show me. But stay off the carpet.
It's the trick window
from A Kill For All Seasons.
Trooper. here. will you? Take this.
Traces of dried mud.
I suspect they go
the length of the hallway.
Footprints?
No. just traces.
Yeah. depending on when
this thing was last cleaned.
this could have happened
at any time. right?
No. that would not explain this.
Analyze that mud.
It will match these traces.
- Take this to Jamie.
- You will find similar samples
leading up the trellis
on the outside of the house.
On the night of the party.
somebody who did not want
to be heard climbing those steps
went to a great deal of trouble
to break into Harlan Thrombey's rooms.
The game is afoot. eh. Watson?
Well. thank you all
for getting together like this.
It isn't legally necessary.
but I thought because you're all in town.
and some of you are leaving soon--
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I would like to gently request
that you all stay in town
until the investigation is completed.
Yeah. well. he's gently requesting.
but I'm gonna have to make that an order.
No one move until we figure this all out.
- What?
- Can we ask why?
- Has something changed?
- No.
No. it hasn't changed?
Or no. we can't ask?
Mr. Stevens...
you may continue.
Right. Well...
The other reason I thought
this gathering would be beneficial
is because Harlan altered his will
a week before he died.
He sealed it.
He asked me not to submit it to the courts
for probate until after his death.
So. if anyone is confused about anything.
we're all together. we can talk.
Although I don't imagine any of it
is going to be that complicated.
Harlan's assets included...
- The house.
which he owned outright.
- Um...
- $60 million.
Yes. $60 million in various cash accounts
and investments.
And of course.
the real asset.
sole ownership of Blood Like Wine.
his publishing company.
He also wrote up a statement
when he was making the changes
and he wanted that read first.
"Dearest Linda. Walter. and Joni.
Some of you may be surprised
by the choice I've made here.
No pleasure was taken in the exclusion.
And its purpose was not to sow
greater discord in the family.
quite the opposite.
Please accept it with grace
and without bitterness. but do accept it.
It's for the best. Dad."
Wow. Well. yeah. not too complex at all.
This will be quick.
"L. Harlan Thrombey.
being of sound mind and body
and yada. yada. yada...
I hereby direct that all my assets.
both liquid and otherwise.
I leave in their entirety
to Marta Cabrera.
My entire ownership
of Blood Like Wine publishing.
I leave in its entirety to Marta Cabrera.
The copyright of its catalog likewise
I leave in its entirety to Marta Cabrera."
What?
- What?
- No.
- That's not... That's-- No.
That can't be.
Can I see that please. Alan?
- Yeah. It's right.
- Please.
- This can't be legal.
- It's right.
- You know. he was--
- Oh. my God.
- Aren't there safeguards?
- There's a mistake.
I don't know what to say.
We're his family. so...
It's not possible.
Are there safeguards against this?
Wasn't in his right mind? Something...
- You know. Alan. listen.
- You know. he was on medication.
Morphine? All right. morphine.
I mean. I don't know.
- She seems like family--
- Alan. you can take
this piece of paper and shove it
right up your ass. and get out!
And. you cops. too. out.
Out! Right now.
- Hey. Linda?
- No. Richard. we need to talk.
We need to fight this thing.
We're not going anywhere.
I said get out!
We are the Thrombeys. goddamn it!
This is still our house!
Oh. sorry.
"Likewise the house at 2 Deerborn Drive
and all belongings therein.
I leave to Marta Cabrera."
Oh. you little bitch!
- You little bitch!
- Linda?
Did you know about this?
Were you in on this from the beginning?
- This is unbelievable!
- No. I just wanna know.
What were you-- What were you doing?
Were you boinking my father?
- "Boinking"?
- No. no. no.
I think everybody just needs
to cool their jets.
You had sex with my grandpa.
you dirty anchor baby!
Now hold your horses.
And in the meantime. I'd maybe run.
Wait. wait. wait. Marta?
- Now. would you please--
- You need to talk to us.
Marta?
Wait a minute. I totally understand how
you must be feeling right now.
You cannot leave!
I don't know what to say. I don't know.
- Calm down. Calm down.
- Marta. please...
Marta. listen. darling--
I don't know what's happening.
I don't know why he--
Guys. I'm also confused. I need to think!
Marta! Are you listening?
I can't catch up!
- I understand.
- Richard! Open up that door!
- You are scaring her!
- I can't open the damn door!
Marta. go. Marta. go.
Marta. you have to understand.
He is our father!
- Marta. listen to me.
- Don't listen to them. I'm here.
I'm not on Twitter anymore.
So DM me on Instagram. okay?
I wanna talk to you.
Ransom!
What the hell's going on?
I think this could be the best thing
to happen to all of you!
What does he mean by that?
Richard. why didn't you stop her?
What am I supposed to do?
Grab the bumper with my teeth?
Okay. seriously. though. what the hell?
Hey. I'll take an extra bowl.
Sure.
You look like you're gonna pass out.
Have you eaten anything today?
Eat.
This is a nightmare.
So why?
- Why?
Hey. This is everything.
There's gotta be a bigger reason why.
and you know it.
Well. how about it had to do more
with you guys than with me?
Yeah.
Yeah. it's the only thing
that makes sense.
Did he tell you anything?
Only that I wasn't getting a cent.
That's because he wanted you
to build something from the ground up--
"Build something from the ground up."
My mother built her business
from the ground up
with a million-dollar loan
from my grandfather.
My father owns none of it.
She made him sign a prenup.
He lives in fear.
I know that's what my grandfather was
trying to protect me from by doing this
and I know I shouldn't say this out loud.
but when he told me. I--
Jesus.
I could a killed him.
After I left the party though.
I was driving.
Nowhere. just in the night.
and I had this...
clarity.
Like. from here on out.
I was gonna have to fend for myself.
And that felt...
good.
The old bastard.
Marta. I know three things.
One. I know he didn't commit suicide.
- What makes you think that?
- I don't think it.
I know it.
Because I knew my granddad.
Maybe you and I were
the only two who knew him.
so you're not gonna bullshit me
on this because. two...
I know lying makes you puke.
'Cause of that mafia game
last Fourth of July.
And three...
I know you just ate
a full plate of baked beans and sausage.
So...
Look me in the eye
and tell me what happened
to my grandfather.
- You asshole.
- Marta.
Tell me everything.
Alan. there have got to be options here.
No.
I don't know how many times
I can repeat the same
two pieces of information.
If Harlan was of sound mind
when he made the changes.
- and we all confirmed that he was--
- Would a sound mind do this?
How-- Sound. how?
The very action speaks to unsoundness.
Not legally. No.
You not liking what he did
does not speak to testamentary capacity.
What about undue influence?
Yeah! Undue influence.
How about that? Huh?
Did you just Google that?
Look. if Marta was manipulating Dad
somehow and if we found out--
If somehow. she had gotten
her hooks into him--
You need a strong case for that.
"Your Honor. she endeared herself to him
through hard work and good humor."
That won't cut the salami.
What about the slayer rule?
I did just Google that.
The slayer rule obviously
doesn't apply here.
Well. what the hell is the slayer rule?
Well. it's if someone is convicted
of killing the person.
they don't get their inheritance.
Not even convicted.
Even if they're held responsible
for their death in civil court.
Like O.J.?
Yes. like O.J.
But Harlan committed suicide.
Detective Blanc?
You said the investigation is ongoing.
You made a point of that.
Do you suspect foul play?
Mr. Blanc. if you please...
There is much that remains unclear.
but yes.
I suspect foul play.
Marta?
I have eliminated no suspects.
You're full of shit.
I don't trust this guy in the tweed suit.
And. Alan. God bless you. you're useless.
Thank you.
There's only one answer to this.
She has to renounce the inheritance.
- She knows it's what she should do.
- That's exactly what she--
Right? No way.
It's the moral thing.
- Mom.
- She'll do it.
If Granddad wanted to give Marta
everything. that's what he wanted.
No.
This wasn't him. He loved us.
He wanted us taken care of.
He wanted you to have an education.
Meg.
you think I can pay for your school?
I know.
Just saying it. it sounds insane.
but it's all true.
And I think Blanc's been on to me
from the start.
I don't care if I go to jail. but my mom.
my sister?
We--
You gonna say something?
I always thought I was the only one
that could beat him at Go.
Always thought that meant something.
Yeah. I know you did.
That night at the party.
my last conversation with him...
My last argument.
that's what he told me about you.
That you beat him at Go
more than I do. and I thought...
"What a strange thing to tell me."
Think I get it now.
Maybe it did mean something.
I'm not gonna tell my family shit.
You're not gonna go to jail.
That detective is not gonna catch you.
And you're not gonna give up the money.
This is what Granddad wanted for you.
Think about what he did
to go through with this.
He wanted this for himself.
he wanted this for the family.
And he wanted it for you.
You've come this far.
Let me help you go all the way.
What's going on? This isn't you.
You could just turn me in right now
and still get your cut of the inheritance.
Why?
Because fuck my family.
I can help you get away with this.
And then.
you're gonna give me
my cut of the inheritance.
Happy ending. Everybody wins.
You. me. Harlan.
Yeah.
Deal?
- Meg.
- Marta...
That was nuts.
I know.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Are you?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine. I--
Look. no one knows
I'm calling you. I just--
I wanted to...
I wanted to say sorry
for how everyone was.
And...
I guess. I wanted to ask.
what are you gonna do?
What do you mean?
Well. the--
You know. with the will.
what are you gonna do?
What do you think I should do?
You should do whatever you think is right.
Look. I--
I think you should give it back to us.
Granddad always took care of us.
You know. we're his family.
And I know he was like family to you.
but we're his actual family.
Yeah.
And look. Marta.
you know this isn't fair.
We've always been good to you
and you're like family.
and we'll take care of you.
but you have to make things right.
You know what's right.
Marta...
Mom's broke.
And she says I'm gonna have
to drop out of school.
No. No. no. Meg.
Listen. I won't let that happen.
Whatever money you need.
I'll give it to you.
I'm here for you. And I want you to know
I'm gonna take care of you.
I promise that.
Okay?
Thanks.
And once I--
Sometimes I think it's a sin
When I feel like I'm winnin'
When I'm losin' again
Okay then.
Did Blanc find anything suspicious
at the house?
Yes. he found mud upstairs.
- Where I broke in through the window.
- Shit.
Identifiable prints?
- No.
- Good. Okay.
Good. Hey...
You lay low for a couple days.
wait for this investigation to blow over.
and it will.
'Cause no matter how good this Blanc guy
thinks he is. he's got nothin'.
Hey. relax.
Marta. get your ass up!
What the hell is happening?
There's a guy here and a bunch of stuff.
Everything's going crazy. Are we rich?
Maybe. Alice. I don't know.
I don't know what that means.
but you better get your ass up. okay?
We don't know much about Marta Cabrera.
- or her exact relationship...
- Oh. my God.
Marta. what is all this?
What did you do?
- Is that here?
- Oh. yeah. it is.
Wait. so is that true?
Are we rich?
This is a story so compelling...
Oh. my God.
...it is as if he had written
the story himself.
Good morning. Mrs. Thrombey.
Why is grief the providence of youth?
I don't know.
But I'd imagine
that age deepens all feelings.
Including grief.
This was a long walk
to offering condolences
for the loss of your son.
And asking you.
if it isn't presumptuous of me.
not to think too harshly of your family...
if I am. as I suspect.
the first to console you.
They're young. aren't they?
One thing I assume of age
is weariness.
Damned if I don't get
more tired every day.
Tired of what I do.
Following arcs like lobbed rocks.
the inevitability of truth.
But the complexity and the gray...
lie not in the truth...
but what you do with the truth
once you have it.
I think you have something
you wanna tell me.
I think you're very perceptive
and very capable
of telling me what you saw
the night of your son's party.
But I'll happily wait.
I'm in no rush.
In fact.
I find it quite pleasant
sitting here with you.
Lawyers were here.
Very big lawyers. it looked like.
They left this stuff and business cards.
And there was a pile of other stuff
when I got home.
I don't like any of this. Marta.
I don't like it either.
I'm slipping out the back.
I'll be back later.
Please don't talk to anyone.
Walt?
Yeah. I came--
Hey. how you doin'?
Walt. I want you to know
that I didn't know about any of this.
- We know you didn't.
- This is--
We know you didn't.
Yeah. we all kind of went
a little crazy yesterday.
- Understandable.
- Yeah.
I haven't even looked at all this yet.
It must just be
local lawyers and accountants
who saw the news
and wanna get a jump on it.
Yeah. I'd be careful of all of it.
Marta. is it your intention
to renounce the inheritance?
This is what Harlan wanted.
Yeah. but...
Harlan put you in
a very hard position here.
I mean... it was unfair of him.
I mean. you see
the kind of press and scrutiny
that this kicks up.
And we know. with your mother...
My mother?
Yeah.
What did Meg tell you?
This isn't about--
You're missing the point.
We don't wanna attack you with this.
but. Marta. if your mother
came into the country illegally.
criminally.
and you've come into this inheritance.
with all the scrutiny that entails.
I'd be afraid that could come to light.
And that's what we wanna avoid here.
We can protect you...
from that happening. or if it happens.
So you're saying that
even if it came to light.
with your family's resources.
you could help me fix it?
Yeah.
Yeah. with the right lawyers. you know?
Not these local guys.
but New York lawyers. DC lawyers.
with enough resources put toward it. yes.
Not that that ever even needs
to come up. but...
yes.
Okay. good.
Okay?
'Cause Harlan gave me all your resources.
So that means with my resources.
I'll be able to fix it.
So I guess I will find the right lawyers.
Uh. Marta. that's--
You better be sure that's...
what you want.
No...
- I don't know-- What's this?
- It's my medical bag tag.
They have my medical bag for some reason.
Okay. but this is a photocopy
of just the header
of a blood toxicology report on Harlan.
Marta. this is gonna show
the morphine overdose.
So I'm screwed?
How do you know all this stuff?
I was Harlan's research assistant
for a summer.
But what kind of blackmail scheme is this?
I mean. the actual evidence is sitting
up the street. at the crime lab.
There's no demands.
there's no meeting place.
What's the point in sending you this?
It could be a half hour.
It could be an hour. It depends.
We wanna make sure...
- So. it could take a while.
- What's the cheese?
- Oh. hey.
- Yeah.
- Thank you. Chief.
- No problem.
5:00 a.m.
Security systems here are all triggered.
Now. this thing went up really quick.
so that means blood stores. records.
anything of that nature. it's all gone.
There were no employees here.
so. thank God for that.
What about security cameras?
Oh. yeah.
Speaking of security.
the surveillance tape
at the Thrombey estate
was all scrambled for some reason.
Yeah.
What's still pending from the autopsy?
Just a report on the blood work.
Blood work?
Holy shit.
This is insane.
I mean. who would blow up
a whole real building
just to blackmail me?
Marta. this means the blackmailer
has the only paper copy
of the thing that can prove your guilt.
You didn't get any other instructions?
No phone call? No e-mail? Nothing?
No.
Well. I haven't checked my e-mail.
There is one.
Yeah. that's it.
"1209 Columbus Road. 10 a.m."
You know what this means. right?
If you destroy that copy.
you're totally in the clear.
Oh. no.
Marta. did you hear me?
Yeah.
Elliott!
We gotta go! We gotta go!
- Okay. Baby Driver.
- Oh. God.
- You regret helping me yet?
- I regret not taking the Beemer.
Oh. shit.
- Vehicles in pursuit on Washington Street.
- No force.
- Make sure you say "no force."
- We got a possible murder suspect.
- I said that. I said that.
Go. Go! Go! Are you flooring it?
I am literally flooring it!
- This is going well.
- I'm pulling over. I'm--
If you miss your chance
to get this tox report. it's all over.
Oh. my God.
Whoa!
Why-- Why are we stopping?
Why are you stopping
in the middle of the road?
Hold on.
Oh. my God.
I'm just pure adrenaline right now.
I feel like I swallowed bees.
Okay.
So where is it? What's the address?
1209 Columbus Road.
Okay. I mean. whatever they want.
- I'll say yes--
- Anything.
You know. just to get that report back.
- Get it back and destroy it.
- Destroy it.
Holy shit. Ransom.
Hey. thank you.
I couldn't do this without you.
Oh. my God.
Get out.
That was the dumbest car chase
of all time.
Put your hands down.
I spoke to Wanetta Thrombey. Greatnana.
Night of the party. she saw someone
climbing the trellis to the third floor.
- Mr. Drysdale. come on.
- Let's go.
- Pat him down. check him out.
- What's going on?
- "Ransom came back." she said.
- Hands on the vehicle.
I don't know what he came back to do.
but we'll find out.
You got anything sharp?
- Watch your head. Thank you.
- Hey. you don't need to thank him.
Did he ask you to drive
when he saw me coming?
Yes.
Blanc. coming with us?
I'll drive with Marta.
Let's go to the police station.
I want a full rundown
on everything he said to you.
I'll catch you up on where we're at.
Strange case from the start.
A case with a hole in the middle.
A doughnut.
I'm just talking through my process here.
Let me know if this is boring.
I feel the noose tightening.
The family is truly desperate.
Desperate motives.
The mystery of who hired me.
The impossibility of the crime.
And yet...
A doughnut.
One central piece.
And if it reveals itself.
the fog would lift.
the arc would resolve.
the Slinky become unkinked.
Do you mind if I stop for a second?
I need to pick something up.
It'll be very quick.
Sure.
It'll be just a few minutes.
Watch the...
door.
Hello?
Listen. I don't know what you want.
Whatever it is. we can work it out.
But we have to figure it out
right here. right now.
And I'm leaving with that report.
Hello?
Fran?
No. no. no. no! Fran?
Oh. my God. Fran.
Can you hear me?
Fran. give me a sign if you can hear me.
- You...
- Yes. it's me. It's Marta.
You called me here. you sent me an e-mail.
That's why I'm here.
Did you take something?
I'm gonna call an ambulance now.
You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be fine. okay? Stay with me.
- Copy...
- What?
Copy...
Stashed...
What? What are you saying?
You did this.
Won't get away with this.
Jesus. stop it!
911. what's your emergency?
The thought of you stays bright
Sometimes I stand
In the middle of the floor
Not going left
Not going...
Oh. Lord.
All right. my friend.
Thank you for the update.
There's no need for that.
I'll bring her in once we get word
that the housekeeper is stable.
It's still touch and go.
All right.
Listen. this is over.
People are getting hurt.
So I'm gonna tell you the truth.
Young Ransom just told
Lieutenant Elliott everything.
Good.
Wait. I hope he didn't cover for me.
Did he tell you the real truth
- about me switching the--
- Yeah.
- And the disguise bit?
- Yes.
And the whole blackmail and--
But why did Fran take my morphine?
I mean. obviously she had swiped
the bag from the house.
but she didn't seem like a user to me.
unless that's why she needed
the blackmail money.
I don't know. It doesn't matter anyway.
I have to tell the Thrombeys myself.
I feel like I owe that to them.
I don't think that's a good idea.
No. I have to do it. I need to do it.
I gave the doctors my number.
so they'll call if anything
changes with Fran.
All right.
I'll round up the Thrombeys at the house.
along with a police escort.
For the arrest after.
You can tell me your whole story
on the drive over.
I don't want any more surprises.
Fran said it was stashed.
the copy. and then she said.
"You did this.
You won't get away with it."
And I called the ambulance.
That's it.
All right.
You ready?
Okay.
Well. has she come to her senses?
Well. she's standing right there. Richard.
She can speak for herself.
- Is the rest of the family here?
- In the living room.
I think that it would be better if we were
to gather again and get this over with.
- Hey.
I'm so sorry I told them about your mom.
Meg. it's okay.
I'm sorry. No-- I was scared.
I just-- I didn't wanna tell them.
I get it.
Trust me.
I understand. It's all right.
I'm sorry.
God. I am so raiding
Fran's stash after this.
I still think this is a bad idea.
but the family is assembled.
I know where the tox report is.
She basically told me where it was.
Anyways. this will tie everything up.
And I just handed it to you.
God. you're not much
of a detective. are you?
Well. to be fair...
you make a pretty lousy murderer.
Perhaps we deserve each other.
You've always been good to me.
And what I'm about to say
isn't gonna be easy
and you're gonna be upset.
But I thought after what you've
gone through the last few days.
that you deserved to hear it from me.
- I--
- Excuse me!
You have not been good to her.
You have all treated her like shit.
to steal back a fortune that you lost
and she deserves.
You're a pack of vultures at the feast!
Knives out. beaks bloody!
Well...
You're not getting bailed out.
not this time.
Miss Cabrera has decided. definitively.
not to renounce the inheritance.
- What?
Furthermore. it will be
my professional recommendation
to the local authorities
that the manner of death
in the case of Harlan Thrombey
is ruled as suicide!
- And the case is closed.
- Blanc?
- What?
- Thank you all for coming. Goodbye.
What's going on? Just tell me--
That's certainly not what I was expecting.
- No.
- Is anybody else confused?
Not what I was expecting to hear at all.
Are you gonna tell me
what the hell is going on?
- Yes. Yes.
- I just wanna come clean. okay?
- It's over.
- Almost.
Blanc. what are we doing?
- What's going on?
- I'm sorry. Officer Wagner.
Keep the family out of this room.
and get 'em out of the house if you can.
But stand by with your additional officer.
Get the family out?
Yes. but not all of them. Would you...
Thank you.
- Blanc.
- Yes. sir.
Come on. what's all this drama?
- Indulge me.
- Blanc.
I told Ransom. Ransom told you.
and I'm telling you now.
it is an immovable fact
that I killed Harlan.
Yes. you did. Yes. he did. Yes. you are.
But-- But. I spoke in the car
about the hole
at the center of this doughnut.
And what you and Harlan did
that fateful night
seems at first glance
to fill that hole perfectly.
A doughnut hole in a doughnut's hole.
But we must look a little closer.
And when we do. we see the doughnut hole
has a hole in its center.
It is not a doughnut hole.
but a smaller doughnut with its own hole
and our doughnut is not whole at all!
Blanc. look. I understand
that this is amusing for you--
Why was I hired?
Why would someone hire me?
Someone fishing for a crime
to reverse the will. Come on.
But I was hired
before the sealed will was read.
So. yes. the person must have known
the contents of the will.
But one step further.
That same person must have known
a crime was committed.
and further...
If the intent was to reverse
Marta's inheritance.
they must have known
that Marta was responsible.
An intriguing combination of factors.
Someone who knew what Marta did
wanted to expose it
but could not reveal how they knew.
Fran!
She was blackmailing me.
She knew what I did.
Yeah. but Fran wanted money.
ergo she did not want the crime exposed.
What if someone in the family had observed
Marta doing something suspicious?
But they would have had
no reason not to speak up.
The answer is not so simple.
Now with the entire solution
in my field of view.
the arc of this case
is a tragedy of errors.
Marta. it will not be easy
for you to hear.
But there is at least
one truly guilty party behind it all.
guilty in the true sense
of acting with malice
and committing a heinous crime
with selfish intent.
Trooper Wagner.
Trooper Wagner?
No.
Marta. I'm so sorry.
I told them everything.
I figured it was up. I'm sorry.
Hey. It's all right. Ransom.
I'm glad you did.
Not exactly everything though.
Is this about what Greatnana told you?
She saw me that night.
She mistook me for Ransom.
We'll get to that.
In the meanwhile.
Mr. Hugh Ransom Drysdale.
you might tell us all why you hired me.
Why I hired you?
You're right. Let's back it up
to the night of the party.
Your argument with Harlan.
What were the overheard words
by the Nazi child
masturbating in the bathroom?
"My will. " and "I'm warning you."
You and Harlan were drama mamas.
You shared a love of twisting the knife
into one another.
You see. I don't believe
he would have slipped it in halfway.
No. no. no.
I submit
Harlan told you everything.
You can't be serious!
Not a red dime or word of my work
to a single one of them. you included.
Marta.
remind me what Ransom said
his conversation with Harlan ended with?
Harlan told him that
I could beat him at Go.
And I asked myself. "Marta?
Why would the topic of the will
have steered around to Marta?"
There is one obvious explanation.
You can't be that crazy. You're not
just gonna throw away your fortune.
No. I'm giving it to Marta.
All of it.
Your Brazilian nurse?
Are you goddamn insane?
I'm sane for the first time in my life.
and I've done it.
If you think I'm gonna let this happen.
- if you think I'll stand here--
- I've made the change to my will.
- It's done.
- I'm warning you!
That's some heavy-duty conjecture.
Granted.
But it is the only way
what comes next makes sense.
So you storm out.
you drive off into the night.
You tell Marta later--
What was it?
Feeling an overwhelming sense of...
Clarity.
That he had to make do for himself
from here on out.
Exactly.
Marta. The will. Harlan.
"Do for yourself."
"You won't get away with this."
And a plan forms.
You return.
careful to avoid the gate's
security camera range.
Then on foot up towards the house.
you sneak in up the trellis.
so as not to be seen
by the rest of the family
who are still having
their party downstairs.
What you need to do will take moments.
But it is essential
that you are alone and undetected.
You knew what medications Harlan took.
You knew what Marta would be
injecting him with that night.
And you knew
if Marta was responsible for his death.
even unintentionally.
the slayer rule would nullify
the changed will
and you would get your share back.
You used the syringes in the kit
to switch the liquids
in the two medication vials.
And as a final precaution...
you took the Naloxone.
the lifesaving antidote.
No. No. no. no. that's impossible.
That is the truth.
Hand me that vial of morphine.
I'll show you.
If he did that. if the meds were switched.
then when I got them mixed up. I...
I accidentally switched them back. so...
I gave Harlan...
The correct doses.
Yes.
But not accidentally.
I taped over the label of these two vials.
The vials themselves are identical.
How'd you know this was the morphine?
I just knew.
You knew because there is the slightest.
almost imperceptible differences
of tincture and viscosity
between the two liquids.
You knew because
you've done it a hundred times.
You gave him the correct medication
because you are a good nurse.
Then Harlan was--
I'm sorry. Marta. But yes.
- Harlan was perfectly fine.
- Oh. my God.
His blood was normal.
The cause of death was truly.
solely suicide.
and you are guilty of nothing
but some damage to the trellis
and a few amateur theatrics.
In fact. if Harlan had listened to you
and called the ambulance...
he would be alive today.
Damn!
A twisted web.
And we are not finished untangling it.
Not yet.
Marta. when Greatnana spotted you
climbing down the trellis. she said...
Ransom? Are you back again already?
"Are you back again already?"
'Cause earlier that night...
Ransom. you're back?
Come on. Marta.
This is "stoopid" with two O's.
You don't have a shred of evidence.
You're just spinning a fairy tale.
Not a shred. no.
Just as we have no real proof
of Marta mixing up the vials.
so it's your word--
You have her confession!
All right. yeah.
Yeah. we do have that.
With your permission.
I'd like to spin a little further.
Much later that night.
you yd have to come back to the house
to retrieve the incriminating
tampered vials.
However. this time the dogs were outside.
They barked. waking Meg.
No matter.
You'll get the vials tomorrow.
But tomorrow brings news.
Not of a medical error and a guilty nurse.
but of a slit throat and a suicide.
Now the circumstances are perfect
for the anonymous hirin' of me.
You know a crime has been committed
by Miss Cabrera.
You need her to be caught for it.
You cannot reveal how you know.
Enter...
Benoit Blanc.
Benny. look. I hear what you're saying.
but this--
The body is discovered early
the next morning.
The police.
the medical examiner. the family.
everyone swarms in
and there is no possible way
you can get to Marta's medical bag
to retrieve the vials.
You must wait for your moment.
when the investigation is over
and you know the house will be empty.
And that is why
you missed the funeral.
There is no one home to wonder
why you're going into Harlan's study.
Or so you think.
Poor Fran.
She witnessed you tampering
with Harlan's medication
in the medical bag.
She did not know what you were doing.
But she knew you were up to no good.
So her mind begins to turn.
Oh. God.
That Hallmark movie she told me about
with Danica McKellar...
Deadly by Surprise.
That's what she was talking about.
She loved Harlan.
She hates Ransom.
So the poor girl decides
to test her theory.
and make this asshole pay.
She gets a copy of the toxicology report.
Now. I will be honest. I have no idea how.
'Cause she has a cousin.
She told me. she has a cousin who works as
a receptionist at the examiner's office.
Well. voilá!
The numbers. they mean nothing to her.
but if Ransom is guilty.
its existence is a threat.
so she photocopies the header
and makes her blackmail note.
So why did she send it to me?
She didn't.
She sent it to Ransom.
And when Mr. Drysdale gets it.
what is his reaction?
Elation.
He still thinks Marta has given Harlan
the tampered drugs.
A blood tox report will prove her guilt.
He goes to the will reading
in high spirits.
ready to see the family tear itself apart.
secure in the knowledge
it will be all undone
when the tox report comes to light.
And then...
Marta's confession.
And everything turns on its head.
He now realizes that Marta
has committed no crime
and the tox report
will prove her innocence.
The changed will is gonna stand.
He has lost.
Unless...
Unless you decide...
- You're not gonna give up the money.
- You've come this far.
Just one step further.
just one last act.
In for a penny. in for a pound.
You decide you are in.
Step one...
Destroy all evidence of Marta's innocence.
Step two.
send her the anonymous e-mail
with a late morning rendezvous time...
And deliver her the blackmail note.
Step three.
keep your appointment with Fran.
Oh. I knew it.
I knew you were a no-good son of a bitch.
I knew Harlan wouldn't just kill himself.
Yes. Fran. you were right.
I knew you were guilty as shit.
And now you're gonna pay for it!
Don't you come near me.
Don't come near me! I'm warning you!
See. now. now the board is set.
Marta will get the blackmail note.
You'll put the pieces together for her.
You'll guide her to the rendezvous.
You'll make the anonymous call
to the police.
they will catch her there
with the body and the burned evidence.
Marta will get arrested for killing Fran
and Harlan.
- She said...
- You did this.
She didn't say. "You did this."
She wasn't talking about me. She said...
Hugh did this.
"Hugh did this."
'Cause you made the help call you "Hugh."
'Cause you're an asshole.
And it would have worked
if we hadn't have brought you in
for questioning
so you could not make your anonymous call.
And if Fran had not stashed
a safety copy of the tox report.
And if Marta had not
outplayed you once again.
By having a kind heart.
By saving Fran's life.
though it meant her losing the inheritance
and going to jail.
She didn't play your game.
She saved Fran's life.
Fran's alive?
Oh. yes.
Fran...
...who will confirm this very story
or something close to it.
And send you. Hugh.
to jail.
Yes?
Doctor. that's great news.
We'll be there soon. Thank you.
She's okay.
She's ready to talk.
Trooper Wagner. if you could
keep Mr. Drysdale in custody
while Lieutenant Elliott.
Miss Cabrera. and myself.
we go to the hospital
and take Fran's statement.
All right. Up. come on.
I'm gonna say this just to you.
No cameras. no courtroom.
just you. 'cause you know it's true.
We allowed you into our home.
We let you watch our granddad.
We welcomed you into our family.
And now you think
you can steal it from us?
You think I'm not gonna fight
to protect my home.
our birthright.
our ancestral family home?
That is hooey.
Harlan. he bought this place in the '80s
- from a Pakistani real estate billionaire.
- Oh. shut up. Blanc!
Shut up! Shut up with that
Kentucky Fried Foghorn Leghorn drawl!
Yeah. I killed Fran. But I guess I didn't.
So what do you have on me?
Nothing. What. attempted murder?
I get arson for the building
and a few other charges.
With a good lawyer. which I have.
I'll be out in no time.
And then you'll see just how much hell
I can wreak on your life.
you vicious little bitch.
What the shit!
That means she's lying!
Yeah. man. we know.
That's right.
Fran's dead.
And you just confessed to her murder.
Well...
In for a penny...
Shit.
Linda!
We've gotta get the attorneys
on the phone right now!
We--
Can I ask.
when did you know I had something to do
with Harlan's death?
From the first moment
you set foot in front of me.
Oh. shit.
I want you to remember something
that's very important.
You won.
not by playing the game Harlan's way...
but yours.
You're a good person.
This family...
I should help them. Right?
Well. I have my opinion.
but I have a feeling
you'll follow your heart.